(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T02:15:37.446272",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
風真いろは生誕LIVE 2026 Wind Trails
[Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 - Wind Trails]
あ、あ、あ、皆様
Ah, ah, ah, everyone...
おー！
Hello!
いいですね！コメント元気ですね！
That's great! The comments are so energetic!
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026
Today, for Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026...
「Wind Trails」にご来場くださいまして
..."Wind Trails", thank you very much...
誠にありがとうございます！
...for joining me today!
いぇーい！
Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the start of the show, I have some requests and announcements.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは
During the show, regarding cameras and smartphones...
電源切られると見られなくなって困るので
If you turn them off, you won't be able to watch, which would be bad,
電源は切らず写真撮影などね
so keep them on, take plenty of photos,
大量にしていただき
and post lots of images on SNS...
当配信のハッシュタグ「#風真いろは生誕ライブ2026」で
...using the hashtag #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2026!
SNSに大量に画像ポストしてください！
Please post tons of screenshots!
目指せ！Xトレンド1位！
Let's aim for the #1 trending spot on X!
よろしくおねがいします！
I'm counting on you all!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると
Ah, but if you take too many photos on your phone,
充電なくなっちゃいそうなんで、
it might run out of battery.
スマホで見てる勢は、充電しっかりしてくださいね。
So those watching on phones, make sure you charge up!
はい、そしてその２！
Alright, and number two!
激しく頭を振る、
Violent headbanging,
激しくペンライトを振るなどはですね、
or waving your penlight too violently...
あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので、
...poses a serious risk of destroying your home.
破壊されてもですね、こちらは責任一切負えませんので、
Even if it gets destroyed, we cannot take any responsibility,
お気をつけください！だめだよ、みんな！
so please be careful! Don't do it, guys!
あ、そしてあと、もう１個。その３！
Ah, and one more thing! Number three!
今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてる奴は、
Anyone trying to prepare Hayashi rice right now...
間に合わないからやめな！絶対間に合わないから！
...won't make it in time, so stop! You definitely won't!
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、
Well, while eating or drinking something,
ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd love for you to sit back and enjoy the show!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、
Now, it's about to start very soon,
今しばらくお待ちください。
so please wait just a little longer.
最後まで見てねーー！
Please watch until the very end!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026!
いくよー！
Here we go!
いっせーのーで
“Ready, set, go!”
鳴り響いた
The start signal resounds,
スタートの合図
it's the start signal.
なぞった線で
The world bound
結んだ世界
by the traced line...
色付けしていく
I'll color it in...
ここから
from this point on.
物心がつく頃
Ever since I can remember,
すでに此処にあった
it was already here.
僕じゃない
The memories of someone...
誰かの記憶は
that are not mine...
夕陽とともに
revive...
蘇る
with the sunset.
古ぼけた絵本を
I reached for the worn-out picture book...
取り出して
and pulled it out.
落書きの中に 1つの
Among the scribbles,
答えを見つけた
I found an answer.
自分の価値に目を疑って防ぎ
Doubting the value of myself,
どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
I could fall down as deep as it goes.
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい
I want to disappear somewhere far from here.
こんな世界じゃ僕は必要ない
I don't need a world like this.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already started.
いっせーのーで声を上げて
“Ready, set, go!” Let out your voice.
聴こえてくるんだ
It reaches my ears.
自分の影の長さに気づく
I notice the length of my shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
It's already that time.
一等星が顔を出した
The brightest star showed itself.
届きそうで手を伸ばした
It felt reachable, so I stretched out my hand.
次は僕についてきなよと
“Next time, follow me,” it says,
どんな暗闇でも
no matter how dark it gets.
もういいかい？まーだだよ
Are you ready? No, not yet.
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has begun to rise.
もういいかい？まーだだよ
Are you ready? No, not yet.
色付けしていくここから
I'll color it in from this point on.
10年後の僕らはすれ違いばかりで
Ten years later, we keep crossing paths.
幻想に想いを馳せては
As I let my thoughts wander into illusions,
戻れないそう思い込んだ
“I can't go back,” I convinced myself.
くたびれた心に追い打ちを
Dealt a final blow to this worn-out heart.
あの頃と変わらない夕陽も何とも思わない
Even the sunset, unchanged from back then, feels like nothing.
自分を信じ歩いていければ
If only I believed in myself and walked on,
どこまでだって昇れるのにな
I could have climbed as high as I wanted.
カットを跨ぐその空白に
In the blank space across the cuts,
大切なもの見落としている
I am overlooking what's truly important.
見つけられないと泣きわめく君へ
To you, who's crying out that you can't find it.
いっせーのーで声を上げて<
“Ready, set, go!” Let out your voice.
聴こえてくるんだ
It reaches my ears.
自分の影の長さに気づく
I notice the length of my shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
It's already that time.
一等賞で駆け抜ける君
You, who runs ahead as the best...
くっついていただけの僕でも
Even for someone like me, who just clung onto you...
君の前を歩けるかな
Can I walk ahead of you?
こんな頼りない僕でも
Even if I am this unreliable.
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま
The treasure chest remains covered in dust.
無くした鍵はずっと君の
The lost key has always...
ポケットの中にあった
been inside your pocket.
散らばっていた全てが
Everything that was scattered around...
今ひとつに重なる
is now coming together as one.
手を取り始めよう
Let's take each other's hands and begin...
僕たちの物語
our story.
一度はいらないと思った
Once, I thought I didn't need it.
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
But now, I feel like I can be proud.
愛おしくて
It's so precious...
掛け声はいつも
The cue is always...
いっせーのーで声を上げて
“Ready, set, go!” Let out your voice.
聴こえてくるんだ
It reaches my ears.
自分の影の長さに気づく
I notice the length of my shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
It's already that time.
一等星が顔を出した
The brightest star showed itself.
届きそうで手を伸ばした
It felt reachable, so I stretched out my hand.
次は僕についてきなよと
“Next time, follow me,” it says,
どんな暗闇でも
no matter how dark it gets.
もういいかい？まーだだよ
Are you ready? No, not yet.
泣きじゃくった声で
With a sobbing voice...
もういいかい？まーだだよ
Are you ready? No, not yet.
笑う君が見えた
I could see you smiling.
もういいかい？まーだだよ
Are you ready? No, not yet.
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has begun to rise.
もういいかい？もういいよ
Are you ready? Yes, I am.
色付けしていくここから
I'll color it in from this point on.
あー…
Ah...
はい！
Alright!
ということで！
And so...
始まりました！
...it has begun!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026...
スタート！
...starts now!
みんな、こんばんは！
Everyone, good evening!
ござるー！
Gozaru!
はい、ということで、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Alright, and so, today's stream hashtag is this!
こちらね、みんな、いっぱいポストして、
Please make lots of posts with this hashtag...
いっぱいかっこいいところ撮ってくださいね！
...and capture lots of my cool moments!
頼むよ！
I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを
The only ones who can show the world...
世の中に知らしめられるのは、お前たちなのだ... あ、お前たちだけなのだから！
...how cool and handsome I am, is you... wait, you guys alone!
よろしくお願いします！
So please make it happen!
はい、そして今回のね、ライブ、タイトルがついております！
Yes! And there's a title for today's live concert!
「Wind Trails」というね、
It's called 'Wind Trails'!
タイトルがついておりますが、
That is the title,
ま、そのまんま訳して、結構気づきの方も多かったんですが、
and as many of you might have already realized by translating it literally,
ま、風の軌跡というね、
it carries the meaning of 'Trails of the Wind'—
あの、意味を込めて付けさせていただき、
referring to my own journey as a wind samurai.
今回ライブ色々頑張って考えさせていただきました！
I put a lot of thought and effort into planning today's live!
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでいただけると嬉しいです！
So, I hope you'll enjoy it until the very end!
そして！1曲目ね、かく恋慕、歌わせていただきました！
And! For the first song, I performed 'Kakurembo'!
どうだったかな？
How did you like it?
はい、そして、今日室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
And also, you thought today's live was indoors, didn't you?
見て！
Look!
曲中にドームが開きました！
The dome roof opened up during the song!
いえーい！すごーい！
Yay! Amazing, right?
やっぱりね、なかなか現地ライブって
You know, it's really hard to get a chance...
できてもさ、青空の下でなかなか歌えることってないので、
...to sing under the blue sky even in actual real-world lives.
いつか、俺たちとお前たちの次元が交わって、
So, until the day our dimensions cross...
空の下で歌えるような世界が来るかもしれないけど、
...and we can sing together under the open sky,
やってみたくてね、今回は、
I really wanted to try it out today.
空の下で歌うっていう、この演出をやらさせていただきました！
So I decided to perform under the open sky like this!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
It's pretty amazing, isn't it?
そしてステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで、
And the stage design is super cool, too!
今日はね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、
I think you'll have plenty of chances to see it today,
ゆっくり隅から隅まで、アーカイブ勢もね、きっといると思うんで、
so take your time to look at every detail, even those watching the archive!
本当に色んな細部こだわってるので、細かく見てくださいね！
We really put a lot of care into the details, so please look closely!
ということで、
And so...
あの、お水飲んでいいですかね？
Um, is it alright if I take a quick sip of water?
お水を... おっ！
The water... Oh!
やめろ！俺の頭をいじ... やめ、やめっ...
Stop! Stop messing with my head... Stop, stop it!
頭をいじくり回されて、ヘトヘトになりました。
They messed with my head so much, I'm already exhausted.
そして水が、今日水を用意してくれたんだよね。
And they prepared this water for me today.
みんなに見える水！
A water bottle that you guys can actually see!
うまい！
Delicious!
うま過ぎる！この、このフリはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うま過ぎる！
It's too good! I shouldn't do this pose or I'll get scolded, but it's delicious!
うまいなー。
So good.
これで、あと1時間やるか。そんなわけにはいかないんで、一回ね、これちょっと返して。
Should I just do this for another hour? That wouldn't work, so let me put this back first.
それじゃあ、ちょっと水分補給もさせていただいて、
Well then, now that I've hydrated myself...
息も整ったんで、
...and caught my breath...
はい、次の曲、早速、やっていきたいと思います！
...I'd like to move on to the next song right away!
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
白線
'Hakusen'.
澄み渡った空に
In the clear blue sky...
描いたあの地平を超えて
...beyond the horizon we envisioned!
はい！はい！
Yeah! Yeah!
もっと！はい！はい！
More! Yeah! Yeah!
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で
It started with a slight anticipation,
そのかけらそっとポケットにしまって
tucking those fragments gently into my pocket.
屋上 遠い空の向こう見ていた
On the rooftop, looking far beyond the distant sky.
この足でどこにいけるかなんて
Where these feet can take me...
わかってないけどわかっているんだ
I might not know, yet somehow I do.
白昼の淡い月に手を伸ばした
I reached my hand out to the pale midday moon.
かすれたエコー でも答えはもうはじめからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
Even with a faint echo, I already had the answer from the start.
メイビー この想いは
Maybe this feeling...
（メイビー この想いは）
...(Maybe this feeling)
マスビー 熱を増して
Must be heating up...
（マスビー 熱を増して）
...(Must be heating up)
ほらね、飛べるんだ
See, I can fly!
もっと高く 高くまで 羽ばたいてみたい
Even higher, I want to spread my wings and fly high.
今日に未来色の軌道描いて 地平の先まで
Tracing a future-colored orbit onto today, to the end of the horizon.
届かない歌はない
There is no song that won't reach,
迷いはいらない
no need to hesitate.
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない
No matter the world or the moment, I won't waver.
アイが在るから
Because love is here!
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line drawn in the clear blue sky.
不安と期待とのアンビバレント
An ambivalence of anxiety and expectation,
でも声はもう気づいてる
but my voice already knows...
もっと高く 高く 高く 高く 飛んでいける
...that I can fly higher, higher, higher, and higher!
途切れ途切れの一縷でも
Even if it was just a broken thread,
紡いでたら一途に変わったよ
spinning it made it wholehearted.
あたりさわりない
Harmless and...
あたりさわりない言葉じゃ覆いきれないほどのマイワールド
My world is too vast to be covered by harmless words
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は他でもないこの心だった
The one calling out for tomorrow was none other than my own heart
言えないでいるその言葉も「言葉」だと足りないだけ
Even the words I can't say, calling them just "words" is not enough
掴んだもの 落としたもの
The things I grasped, the things I dropped...
転んだって立って見えた視界から
...from the view I saw after falling and standing back up
ロックユー！解き放って！
Rock you! Release it!
フォーユー！響きだして！
For you! Start echoing!
景色変えてゆく
Changing the scenery
まだ遠く遠くまで広がった空に
Into the sky that spreads far, far away
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんてちっぽけだけど
This first step I'm finally taking is so tiny, but...
届かない場所へと続いていく
...it continues to places out of reach
どんな風に雨に消えない白線を描く
I'll draw a white line that won't fade in any wind or rain
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいていたい
I want to flap my wings higher and higher
そして彼方色で繋ぐループ 地平で待ってて
Connecting a loop with colors beyond, wait for me at the horizon
もう願いに嘘はない ここが好き
There are no more lies in my wishes, I love it here
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く アイが在るから
Any world, any moment will shine because love is here
今はただ想うこと言えばいい「愛しているよ！」
For now, I just need to say what's on my mind: "I love you!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky
葛藤したいとアンビバレント
Conflict and ambivalence
でも君はもう気付いてる
But you have already noticed
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
We can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっと...
More...
鏡よ教えて 私の証はどこにあるのだろう
Mirror, mirror, tell me, where is the proof of my existence?
わからない わからないよ
I don't know, I don't know
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Comparing myself to others only makes me feel empty
あのノイズが海鳴りのように涙を奪う
That noise steals my tears like the roaring of the sea
切り取った風景を道標にしよう そうだ
Let's make this captured scenery our guidepost, yes
傷ついた感情も連れて行くから
Because I'll take even my hurt feelings with me
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
The softly echoing campanella, I can feel a new future
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ 遠くまで
Even if it's scary, we have to move forward, far away
もっと もっと 届けこの祈りよ光となれ
More, more, let this prayer reach and become the light
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More, more, even if it's little by little, let the answer that is "me"...
もっと...
More...
夜空よ教えて 私の証は輝けるのかな
Night sky, tell me, will the proof of my existence be able to shine?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I want to find it
誰かの決めたルールは 苦しくなるだけ
Rules decided by someone else only make things painful
ねえノイズも光に変えるよ 心に誓う
Hey, I swear to my heart, I will turn even the noise into light
錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう ほら
Let's turn the gears of our rusted fate, look
着飾った感情は脱ぎ捨てるから
Because I will cast off my dressed-up emotions
そっと紡ぐストーリー 叶えたい願いを信じてる
The softly spun story, I believe in the wishes I want to come true
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ 全力で
With our heads held high, we have to sing with all our might
もっと もっと やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
More, more, until the day it finally turns into a song of hope
もっと もっと 悩みながらでいい 全てが宝物
More, more, it's fine to worry, everything is a treasure
いつの日かこの声を受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you would receive this voice of mine
この言葉を君に もう大丈夫 一人じゃない
These words are for you: "It's okay now, you are not alone"
強い想いを
These strong feelings...
繋ぐよ 一歩踏み出してみた 優しく世界は微笑む
...I will connect them. I tried taking a step, and the world gently smiles
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて さあ行こう
Surrendering yourself to your throbbing heart, come on, let's go!
そっと響くカンパネラ
The softly echoing campanella
新しい未来を感じてる
I feel a new future
怖くたって進むしかないでしょう 遠くまで
Even if we're scared, we have to move forward, far away
もっと もっと
More and more
届け この祈りよ 光となって
Reach out, this prayer, become the light
もっと もっと
More and more
少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
Even if it's little by little, the answer that is me
もっと
More
雨とペトラ
[Title: Rain and Petra]
誰かが言った いつか空は 灰になって落ちるって
Someone said that one day the sky would turn to ash and fall
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
Eating away at days in a world of delusions
境界線を引いてしまうのも 共感覚のせいにして
Blaming synesthesia for drawing boundaries
街の灯の海で 居場所を探している
Searching for a place to belong in the sea of city lights
何処へ行くにも この足は
Wherever they go, these feet of mine
退屈に染まって動かない
Are dyed in boredom and won't move
少しだけ先の景色が
If only the view a little further ahead
見たいだけなのにな
Was all I wanted to see
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely
頬を濡らしてしまう
It will wet my cheeks
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered become so dear
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more
遠く霞んでしまう
They will haze over far away
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown loud!
誰かが言った いつか溜息は 夜に化けて歌を歌う
Someone said that one day sighs would turn into the night and sing a song
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
Eating away at days in a world of delusions
優しい嘘を なぞったせいで
Because I traced a gentle lie
離れる声に気づかない
I didn't notice the voice growing distant
溶けた月が 足元に落ちて
The melted moon fell at my feet
静かに揺れていた
Quietly swaying
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったらきっと
If night falls, if night falls, surely
今日を責めてしまう
It will blame today
満たされない日々の底で 夢を見ているだけ
Just dreaming at the bottom of these unfulfilled days
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしてもずっと
Even if I look away, even if I look away, always
後悔と愛の隙間
In the gap between regret and love
取り残されてしまう前に 手を伸ばしてくれ
Reach out your hand before I get left behind!
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely
湿るアスファルトを 背に映してうつむいた
Reflecting the damp asphalt on my back, I looked down
一人ぼっちで また明日に期待をして
All alone, expecting something from tomorrow again
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely
頬を濡らしてしまう
It will wet my cheeks
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered become so dear
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more
遠く霞んでしまう
They will haze over far away
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown loud!
群青讃歌
[Title: Gunjo Sanka]
繋がっていたいと信じられる言葉
Words that make us believe we want to stay connected
だってもう昨日の僕らにさよなら
Because it's time to say goodbye to our yesterday selves
青い春を過ごした
We spent our youth together,
遠い稲妻
like a distant lightning bolt.
そっと泣いて前だけを向けたら
If I could gently cry and just look forward,
きっとどんなに楽になれていただろうな
how much easier it surely would have been.
この心を揺らした一瞬の望みは
This fleeting hope that shook my heart...
ないものねだりはやめだ
Stop wishing for what you don't have.
未完成人間
We are incomplete human beings.
素晴らしき世界だけが
In this wonderful world alone,
答えを握ってる
lies the answer we seek.
諦めてしまうほど
To the point of almost giving up,
この先たくさんの後悔が君を待ってるけど
so many regrets lie ahead waiting for you, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more! I won't hesitate anymore!
この傷も愛おしく
Even these wounds are dear to me.
燃えてしまうほど重ねてしまうよ
I will pile them up until they burn away.
不格好なままでいいから
Because it's okay to be clumsy!
走れ その歩幅で
Run, with your own stride!
叫べ 声とどろかせてくれ
Scream, let your voice resound!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ未来 照らして
and illuminate the future we spin together right now!
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't even know each other's faces or names,
たった一つの音をかき鳴らす悪戯
make mischief by playing a single sound.
みたいな
It's almost like...
奇跡のような切なさ
a miracle-like bittersweetness.
あっという間に流れる時が
As time flows by in the blink of an eye,
ありのままであり続ける怖さが
the fear of continuing to remain just as we are...
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
Though we can't retrieve the time we've lost...
過去振り返ってばかりじゃ泣いたっていいんだ
It's fine to cry if you're only looking back at the past.
悔しさと痛みだけが
Only the frustration and pain...
君を肯定するから
will validate who you are.
大人になったら忘れてしまうの
Will we forget everything once we grow up?
君と約束をした場所はもうない
The place where we made our promise is no longer here.
覚えていたいよ
But I want to remember it.
思い出も愛おしく
Even these memories are precious.
燃えてしまうほど重ねてしまうよ
I will pile them up until they burn away.
不格好なままでいいから
Because it's okay to be clumsy!
その声はどこまでもなり響いて
Let that voice echo far and wide!
不確かな理由を抱いて ここまで来たんだ
Embracing uncertain reasons, we've come all this way.
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
This journey is far from over.
いつしか思いは形になる
Sometime, our feelings will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる朝 忘れられないままだから
Because I still can't forget this pure white morning...
諦めてしまうほど
To the point of almost giving up,
この先たくさんの...
so many things lie ahead...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more! I won't hesitate anymore!
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Irreplaceable things are overflowing.
答えは君のその胸の中に
The answer lies deep within your chest.
離さないで 物語は一歩前へ
Don't let go, let the story take a step forward.
諦めてしまうほど
To the point of almost giving up,
この先たくさんの後悔が君を待ってるけど
so many regrets lie ahead waiting for you, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more! I won't hesitate anymore!
この傷も愛おしく
Even these wounds are dear to me.
燃えてしまうほど重ねてしまうよ
I will pile them up until they burn away.
不格好なままでいいから
Because it's okay to be clumsy!
走れ その歩幅で
Run, with your own stride!
叫べ 声とどろかせてくれ
Scream, let your voice resound!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ未来 照らして
and illuminate the future we spin together right now!
Yeah, woo...
六兆年と一夜物語
Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story
名もない時代の集落の
In a settlement of an nameless era,
名もない幼い少年の
lived a young nameless boy.
誰も知らないおとぎばなし
This is a fairy tale that nobody knows.
おとぎばなし
A fairy tale
生まれついた時から
From the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
As an outcast, a demon's child,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
I received a punishment too heavy for this body.
悲しいことは 何もないけど
Though there is nothing to be sad about,
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
As I am pulled by the hand at sunset...
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
叱られた後のやさしさも
Not even the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
Nor the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は本当は本当は本当に寒いんだ
But actually, actually, actually, I am so cold.
死なない 死なない 僕はなんで死なない？
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even dream a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎばなしは
The fairy tale that nobody knows...
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and vanished.
吐き出す様な暴力と
With violent words spat out,
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and days filled with despising eyes,
君はいつしかそこに立ってた
before I knew it, you were standing there.
話しかけちゃだめなのに
Even though you shouldn't speak to me,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name," you said.
ごめんね 名前も 舌も無いんだ
I'm sorry, I have neither a name nor a tongue.
僕の居場所は 何処にも無いのに
Even though I have no place to belong,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," you pulled my hand.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
君はもう子供じゃないことも
Not even that you are no longer a child,
慣れない 他人の 手の温もりは
Nor that the unfamiliar warmth of someone else's hand
ただ本当に本当に本当に本当にのことなんだ
is actually, truly, really real.
やめない やめない 君はなんでやめない？
Don't stop, don't stop, why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if they find us.
雨上がりに 忌み子がふたり
After the rain, two outcasts...
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were sucked into the sunset and vanished.
日が暮れて 夜が明けて
The sun set, and the night broke,
遊び疲れて 捕まって
tired of playing, we got caught.
こんな世界 僕と君以外
In a world like this, if everyone but you and me
皆いなくなればいいのにな
would just disappear, it would be so nice...
If everyone would just disappear...
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
Unknown, unknown voices can be heard,
僕と君以外の 全人類
all of humanity except for you and me,
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
without even a moment to resist, were pulled by the hand,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
and sucked into the sunset, they vanished.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
これからのことも 君の名も
Neither about the future, nor even your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
But right now, right now, thinking that this is fine,
ただ本当に本当に本当に本当に思うんだ
I truly, really, honestly think so.
知らない 知らない あの耳鳴りは
Unknown, unknown, that ringing in my ears...
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and vanished.
風を置いて
Leaving the wind behind,
雨を抜けて
pushing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in all your glory!
あぁ、夜風に揺られている
Ah, swaying in the night wind,
折れないように怯えている
afraid that I might break.
ずっと雨に濡らされている
Constantly soaked by the rain,
またどうしたって凍えてしまったんだ
somehow I ended up freezing once again.
誰かこの声に応答して
Someone, please respond to this voice,
痛がるばっかで
as it only hurts,
咲けないままのハートを
leaving my heart unable to bloom.
あぁ、今 見逃せないくらい綺麗に咲かせたいんだ
Ah, now I want to make it bloom beautifully enough to not be missed!
光っていた未来が
The future that was once shining,
ずっと待っていた世界が
the world that has been waiting all along,
きらめく音の中にあるなら
if it lies within the sparkling sounds,
最低で最悪な涙も
then even the worst and most awful tears,
痛がりで嫌いな声も
and the painful, hated voice,
連れていきたいんだ全部
I want to bring it all along.
不完全な毎日が
These imperfect everyday lives,
一瞬のカケラたちが
these fleeting fragments,
重なってこんな歌を奏でたら
if they overlap and play a song like this...
それは
Then,
言葉だけじゃ届かない距離をきっと
a distance that words alone cannot reach,
飛び越えて結ぶ
it will surely leap across and connect us.
きっと輪を描いていく
It will surely draw a circle...
もっとペース上げてく
Speeding up our pace even more
転ばないように乗って乗って浮いて
Riding along, floating so we don't fall
ペダルを回せ
Spin those pedals
グルグル回せ
Spin them round and round
一歩ずつペダルを踏んでく
Step by step, pushing down on the pedals
ここからが本番だ 乗って
From here on, it's the real deal, get on!
迷ったら踊れ
If you get lost, just dance
事態は一変
The situation completely changes
テールランプお構いなしのイナズマになって
Become a bolt of lightning, ignoring the tail lights
声を枯らせ
Let your voice go hoarse
泥だらけになっても生きていたい
I want to live even if I get covered in mud
ほら あの空で合流して
Look, join together in that sky
朝が満たすまで
Until the morning fills the world
それぞれの星を探そう
Let's search for our own stars
ねえ 今
Hey, right now
同じことを思っていたんだって
I was thinking the exact same thing
ほら
See
話さなくても分かり合えた
We understood each other without speaking
ああ こんな嬉しさをずっと待ってみたかった
Ah, I've always wanted to wait for a joy like this
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
The shining future, the world we've been waiting for
煌めいて目の前にあるから
Is sparkling right in front of our eyes
瞬きの刹那まで
Until the blink of an eye
このストーリーの最後まで
Until the very end of this story
輝く花でいたいんだ
I want to be a blooming, shining flower
不完全な私たちが 一瞬の欠片たちが
Our imperfect selves, our fleeting fragments
重なってこんな歌を奏でた
Overlap to play a song like this
それは 夢見るだけじゃ叶わない想いもずっと
Even desires that won't come true just by dreaming
新しくしていく
We will continue to renew them
ずっと追いかけていこう
Let's keep chasing after them forever
風を抱いて 雨を抜けて
Embracing the wind, passing through the rain
咲き誇れ 満天の空へ
Bloom in full glory toward the starry sky
ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath Oblige
世界中のすべての人間に
To be liked by all the humans in the world
好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
would feel pretty disgusting.
だけど一つになれない教室で
But in a classroom where we can't become one,
君と二人 手を繋いでいたいの
I want to hold hands with you, just the two of us.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて
Raising a white flag to the violence of numbers,
悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
killing bad feelings, "say cheese!"
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス
A sweet deep kiss of post-truth,
エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
an erotically warped love and peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する
Self-centered laser guns firing wildly,
強者のナンセンス
nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールでつくる
An haute couture creation...
殺しのライセンス
...a license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
Musical chairs that created division,
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
a babe delivered via painless childbirth.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
We call this grand in-crowd hype "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live, but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die, but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live, but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die, but I'm told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ？
Is boasting about happiness bad?
不幸嘆いてもダメ？
Is lamenting misfortune bad too?
図々しい言葉を避け
Avoiding impudent words,
明るい未来のため
all for a bright future.
さん はい
One, two...
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
さん はい
One, two...
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず
If you please one side, you offend the other.
譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
Giving, taking, protecting, and passing each other by.
地雷原で立ち止まり
Stopping dead in a minefield,
大人しく犬になるんだ ワン
I'll quietly become a dog. Woof!
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige...
I love you
息苦しい日々の水面下
Beneath the surface of these suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
a flower of blood wavers and smokes.
ぼくらは
We...
コンプレックス コンプレックス コンプレックス コンプレックスを武器に
...fight with our complexes...
争う
...as weapons.
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For our own convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを
holding our breath...
強制する
...is forced upon us.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating...
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live, but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die, but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live, but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die, but I'm told to live.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す
Wielding a chainsaw in "self-defense",
まともな人たちが怖いよ
those "sane" people are terrifying.
愛憎爆発 春嵐漫々
Love and hate exploding, spring storm raging,
日々だんだん大事なものが消えていくよ
day by day, important things gradually disappear.
さん はい
One, two...
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
さん はい
One, two...
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 逆恨み
Empathy, envy, jealousy, and spite...
黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
Black tears spill over...
醜い感情が吹き出し
Ugly emotions erupt...
息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Suffocating, suffocating...
I'm suffocating, suffocating...
息を止める 息を止める
Hold my breath, hold my breath...
息を合わせる 息を合わせる
Synchronizing, synchronizing our breaths...
ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath oblige...
I love you
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect what each of us loves,
君と防空壕で呼吸する
I breathe with you in the air-raid shelter.
酸素が足りない...
I need oxygen...
酸素が足りないんですけど。
I don't have enough oxygen...
はい。えー、2曲続けてやらせていただきました。
Yes, I performed two songs in a row.
はい、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Yes, how did you like them?
この前の配信で話したんですけど、
I talked about this in my previous stream,
あの、一部人間じゃないやつがあるって言ってたのが、
about how some songs are not meant for humans...
この『ノンブレス・オブリージュ』と、先ほどソロでやらせていただいた『六兆年と一夜物語』でした。
It was this "Non-breath Oblige" and "Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story" which I just sang.
はい。ちょっと...
Yes... I mean,
純粋にすごく心配だったんですけど、
I was honestly so worried about them,
なんとかね、歌えてよかったという、いま、すごい
but I'm so glad I somehow managed to sing them...
安心でいま震えております。
I'm so relieved that I'm shaking right now.
はい、というわけでここまでたくさん歌わせていただきましたが、
Well, we've performed many songs up to this point,
皆さん、いかがですかー？
everyone, how are you enjoying it?
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって、あずきちと、
We had so many amazing guests join us, AZKi-chan,
あと、みお先輩、フレア先輩、おかゆ先輩、ねね先輩も！
and Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, Okayu-senpai, Nene-senpai too!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
あの本当にみんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きなやつを、
I chose songs I really wanted to sing with everyone, my favorites,
「この人にこれを歌ってるとこ聞きたい！」っていう気持ちで選んで、
thinking "I want to hear them sing this!"...
一緒にやらせていただきました。本当にありがとうございました！
and we performed them together. Thank you so much!
先輩たち、ありがとうー！
Thank you so much, senpais!
ちょっと一回水飲んでもいいですか？水を飲ませてくれ！
Wait, can I drink some water? Let me have some water!
よいしょ。
There we go...
はい。
Okay.
ふぅ、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Whew, I've calmed down a bit.
はい、ということで、まだまだ続くんでね。
Alright, there's still more to come!
次の曲行きたいと思うんですけど、次の曲は、あの、
So I'd like to perform the next song. This next one...
昨日のトークでもめっちゃリクエスト上がってて、
had tons of requests in yesterday's talk too,
その前からもずっとリクエスト上がってて、
and has been highly requested since long before that.
「これは生誕ライブにやりたいな」ってことでずっととっておいた曲です。
I saved it, thinking "I definitely want to do this for my birthday live!"
なんで、楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
So, I hope you will all enjoy it.
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
『ray』
ray
お別れしたのはもっと
It seems like it was a long time ago
前の事だったような
that we said goodbye...
悲しい光は封じ込めて
I locked away the sad light,
踵すり減らしたんだ
wearing down my heels.
君といた時は見えた
When I was with you, I could see it.
今は見えなくなった
Now I can no longer see it.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと
Vaguely searching for a transparent comet,
でもそれだけ探している
but that's all I'm looking for.
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ
I sang songs so often,
その時だけのメロディーを
creating melodies just for that moment.
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all,
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
because I was able to feel properly lonely.
いつまでどこまでなんて
How far, for how long...
正常か異常かなんて
Whether it's normal or abnormal...
考える暇も無い程
I don't even have time to think,
歩くのは大変だ
it's so hard just to walk.
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's much better to have fun.
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll just fake it and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ
It's alright.
あの痛みは忘れたって消えやしない
That pain won't disappear even if forgotten.
理想で作った道を
The road built on ideals,
現実が塗り替えていくよ
reality is repainting as we go.
思い出はその軌跡の上で
Memories remain upon that trajectory,
輝きになって残っている
turning into a lingering brilliance.
お別れしたのは何で
Why did we say goodbye?
何のためだったんだろうな
What was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light stretches my shadow,
前に長く伸ばしている
reaching far out ahead of me.
...影を
...my shadow
前に長く伸ばしている
...stretches long before me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever,
時間がある時眠るよ
and I sleep when I have the time.
夢だと解るその中で
Even in the midst of what I know is a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll see you and then go on my way again.
晴天とはほど遠い
It is far from a clear sky,
終わらない暗闇にも
but even in this never-ending darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら
if I call a star to mind,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'm instantly in the middle of the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
and even if I wear new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
it's alright; that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't fade away even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
I'm sure there was something I wanted to convey.
おそらくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It was probably just a cliché, but even so...
お別れした事は
Our farewell
出会った事と繋がっている
is connected to our meeting.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet,
透明だから無くなりはしない
since it's transparent, will never fade away.
◯✕△どれかなんて
Circle, cross, or triangle—whichever it is,
皆と比べてどうかなんて
or how I compare to everyone else,
確かめる間も無い程
without even a moment to check,
生きるのは最高だ
living is the absolute best!
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll just cover it up and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's alright; that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't fade away even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の
It's alright; at the beginning
始まりには君がいる
of this light, you are here.
はい、ということで、rayでしたー！
Alright, so that was "ray"!
はぁ、どうでしたでしょうか？
Whew, how did you like it?
めっちゃエ、エモい、エモい感じになりましたね！はい！
It felt super, super emotional! Yes!
ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water for a second?
水、水が...
Water... where is the water...
これ...
This one...
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水。いいだろう？風真いろは特注だぜ！
Water that never decreases no matter how much you drink. Great, right? It's custom-made for Kazama Iroha!
よいしょ、ちょっと待って。
Hold on, give me a second.
よし、はい！
Okay, there!
というわけで、次のね、曲にいきたいと思うんですけど、
With that, I'd like to move on to the next song, but...
まああの、昨日の歌枠で、ちょっと匂わせをしておいたのですが、本日ですね、
I dropped a little hint during yesterday's singing stream, but today...
あの、視聴者参加型3D生ライブとなっておりまして、
...this is an interactive viewer-participation 3D live stream!
はい！今回はですね、みなさんに投票をしていただいて、次に歌う曲、
Yes! This time, I want you all to vote to decide...
決めたいと思います！
...the next song I'll sing!
「なんじゃらほい」って思うかもしれないんですけど、「視聴者参加型・曲決め合戦」ということです！
You might wonder what that is, but it's an interactive viewer song-decision battle!
それではテロップどうぞ！
Now, screen overlay, please!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
えー、「ANIMA」か「ただ声一つ」。
Either "ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitsu."
どっちか！
Which one?
で、投票が少なかった方も、このあとメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので、
And even the one with fewer votes will be sung during the members-only encore stream afterward,
よろしくお願いします！
so please look forward to it!
いや、どちらも名曲で、迷いますよね。
Both are such great songs, it's hard to choose, right?
今、スタッフのひとりと、どっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます。
Actually, I've placed a bet with one of the staff members on which one will win.
あの、どっちに賭けてるとか言わないんで、さあ、みんな、これで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか、
I won't say which one I bet on, but everyone, whether my next treats are fancy or not...
裏で決まるからな！
...is decided behind the scenes!
はい、というわけで、さっそく投票を開始していきたいと思います！大体時間は1分ぐらいですかね？
All right then, let's start the voting right away! It'll run for about one minute.
それでは、よーい、スタート！
And... ready, start!
チャットきた？
Are the chat messages coming in?
今、きたかな？
I think they're coming in now.
お、来た来た来た！来た来た来た！
Oh, here it is! It's finally up!
はい、じゃあみんな、投票ボタン押してね！
Alright, everyone press the voting button!
じゃあみんなが投票やってる間に、ゆっくり
While everyone is voting, I'll slowly...
みんなの所回すために帰るわ、メインステージ。
go back to the main stage to look around.
じゃ、移動ですよ。移動〜！
Now, I'm moving! Moving!
はい、というわけで、みなさん投票した？できてる？
Alright, so did everyone vote? Were you able to?
どっちかだよ！
You have to choose one!
ちょっと両方は、両方はちょっとあれだからね。
Both... doing both is a bit tricky, you see.
ちょっと、どっちか、どっちか、どっちかでお願いします！
Please choose one or the other!
そういえば今、なんだかんだこうやって歩かせてもらってますが、
By the way, I'm walking around like this,
実はね、なにげに、ファーストミッション衣装がね、
but actually, this First Mission outfit...
見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのが初めてだったりするんだけど。
it's the first time I'm slowly showing it off.
そう、ここで、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。尺稼ぎじゃないよ！
Right, let me do some promo here. It's not to buy time!
宣伝ね。この後メン限でアフターライブがあるんですけど、
It's promo. We have a member-only after-live later,
そのね、時に、もっとこの、かっこいいところをね、
and I'll show you many more of these
いっぱい見せますので。
cool sides of mine then.
なんでぜひよかったらメン限のアフターライブにもお越しください！
So please come to the member-only after-live if you'd like!
っていう宣伝も入れつつ、みんな入れた？
While throwing in that promo... did everyone vote?
みんな入れた？
Did everyone vote?
ていうか凄いなこれ、花道。長くない？
By the way, this runway is amazing. Isn't it long?
なが、長くない？これ現地ライブでもやりたいな。
Is- Isn't it long? I'd love to do this in person too.
はい。もうだいぶかっこいい風真いろはさんをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが。
Alright. I've shown you a lot of the cool Kazama Iroha.
いやでもどっちかな、これ。「ANIMA」はね、みんな、
But I wonder which one it is. "ANIMA" is, you know,
知っての通り、あの、かっこいい、かっこいい、で。
as everyone knows, very cool.
「ただ声一つ」はしっとり、しっとりなんでね、
While "Tada Koe Hitotsu" is gentle and sweet.
ちょっとこれ好みが分かれると思いますが。
I guess preferences might split on this.
はい。いや、きっとね、どっちやってもみんなかっこいいって言ってくれるよね？
But no matter which one, everyone will call me cool, right?
言ってくれるよね？言ってくれる？
You will, right? You will?
あ、言ってくれる。あ、言ってくれる。言ってくれる。
Ah, you will. Oh, you will. You will.
あ、カメラは言ってくれるってことで。はい、というわけでみんなもう大丈夫かな？
Ah, the camera says yes. Alright, is everyone good?
OK？じゃあそろそろ終わっちゃいますかね？
OK? Then shall we end it soon?
早く早く早く！早く投票してね！
Hurry, hurry, hurry! Vote quickly!
お、終わった？終わったよね？スタッフさん。終わった？
Oh, is it over? It's over, right? Staff? Is it over?
早かった？歩くの。終わった？終わった、終わった、終わったかな？
Was my walking fast? Is it over? Over? I wonder if it's over.
あ、なんか終わったらしい。
Ah, looks like it's over.
今、賭けをしているスタッフと睨めっこしてます。
Right now, I'm staring down the staff members who placed bets.
それでは、結果発表タイム！
Now then, time to announce the results!
どぅるるるるるるるるるるるるるるるるるる、じゃじゃん！
Drumroll... Tadah!
アンケートの結果、「ANIMA」になったみたいです！
According to the poll results, it looks like "ANIMA" won!
あ、これはあの、賭けに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the movement of someone who won their bet.
はい、それでは期待してます！よっしゃー！
Yes, so I have high hopes! Yes!
というわけで、あの、賭けにも勝ち、皆さんにも選んでいただき、とてもありがたい限りですね。
So, winning the bet and having you all choose it makes me extremely grateful.
あの「ただ声一つ」の方も、この後メンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに。
"Tada Koe Hitotsu" will be sung during the member-only part later, so look forward to that too.
というわけで、早速歌っていきましょうか。
So, let's start singing right away.
それでは聴いてください。「ANIMA」
Please listen. "ANIMA".
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
「もういっそ折れたままで」
“I might as well stay broken”
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど 強くないよ ほら
I'm not strong enough to cast it aside or run away. Look...
もう一度
Once again...
鼓動、高鳴る 何が正しいかなんてわからないけど
my heart beats fast, even though I don't know what is right.
形のないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Only the shapeless things become truly precious.
something true
飾らない言葉だけが 強く結ばれてる
Only unadorned words tie us tightly together.
over soul
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Even if I stumble and roll again, I won't break.
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Though I'm just hurt and acting tough, I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm searching for the shape of my soul.
深い地の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Alone deep underground, searching for the door and key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Look, the fairy tales...
泡の様に全部消えて 葛藤、残像だけ
...disappear like bubbles, leaving only conflict and afterimages.
次の頁へ
Onward to the next page.
伸びていく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
The growing branches split, going their separate ways.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories...
強く根を張ってる
...are growing strong roots.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない
Still piercing and losing, but still not giving up.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind and falling out, but I still want to tell you...
魂の日々を
...of the days of the soul...
魂の意思を
...of the will of the soul.
ずっと
Forever...
魂の色は
What color...
何色ですか
...is your soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
what color are you, who are living?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling again, but still not breaking.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, but I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm checking the shape of my soul.
ずっと
Forever...
はい！ということで、ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
Yes! And with that, I sang "ANIMA"!
はぁ〜カロリー高い方だったな！ちょっと水、水ください。
Phew, that was a high-calorie song! Let me get some water, please.
カロリー高い方だった。あぶない。
That was a high-calorie song. That was close.
あ、あ、あ、すみません。あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すのを忘れていました。
Ah, ah, ah, sorry. Um, I naturally forgot to hand back the microphone.
ははは！やばい、お変になってなかったらいいな。すみません。
Hahaha! Oh no, I hope it didn't sound weird. Sorry about that.
ナチュラルに。スタッフさんがすっごい手伸ばしてくれてたのに、疲れすぎてここ硬直してた。
The staff was reaching out so much, but I was so tired my arm just froze up.
はい。水うまい。
Yes. Water is delicious.
枯れない水のおかげで生きていけてます。
Thanks to this never-ending water, I'm staying alive.
はい。じゃちょっとこれ返して。
Alright. Let me hand this back.
はい。それではですね、まぁちょっとまだまだ続くんですけど、ここいらで一旦
Alright, so, we still have a lot more to go, but let's take a break here...
重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います！
...to have some major announcements!
じゃあ、まずはいつものから行くか！じゃあ、まずはこちら！
Now, shall we start with the usual? First up is this!
風真いろは、誕生日記念2026出ます！ドンドコドンドコドンドン！
Kazama Iroha's Birthday Celebration 2026 goods are coming out! *drumroll*!
いや〜なんか良さそうなラインナップですね〜
Wow, it looks like a really great lineup!
はい。今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで、皆さん楽しみにしていてほしいです。では、1つずつ商品見ていきましょう。
Yes, these are all items we've put a lot of care into again, so I hope you all look forward to them. Now, let's look at each item one by one.
まずは、こちら！
First, this!
タペストリーが出ます！
The tapestry is coming out!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね。イラストはもちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、
It's actually been a really long time since I released a tapestry as personal merchandise. The illustration is newly drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei...
雨上がりの青空の下で、もう本当にね、このステージみたいな感じでライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで書いていただきました。
...and it depicts Kazama Iroha performing a live show under a blue sky after the rain, just like on this stage.
ありがとうございます！いや〜めっちゃいいよね。飾ってね。
Thank you so much! It's really nice, isn't it? Please display it!
続いてはこちら！フード付きタオル！
Next up is this! The hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
Yes, it's a hooded towel featuring the same illustration as the tapestry. The hood is shaped like Pokobe's face and is detachable.
いやなんか、この間ね、あの、ホロックスのライブあったじゃん？で、なんかダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど、
Actually, the other day we had the holoX live concert, right? And my dance instructor told me...
なんか「風真は異様にタオル購入率が良かった」らしいな、お前たち。首にいっぱい巻いてくれて、偉いぞ！
...that apparently, "Kazama had an unusually high towel purchase rate!" You guys wrapped them around your necks. Good job!
フード付きタオル...
The hooded towel...
これでじにんぽこべえごっこができるようになります。
With this, you can play pretend as De-nin Pokobei!
じにんぽこべえごっこをしたい方、
For those who want to play pretend as De-nin Pokobei...
まあ、取り外してそのまま飾りたい方もね、どうぞ。
Or if you just want to detach it and display it, go ahead.
はい。そしてお次は、こちら。
All right, and next is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
The plastic bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいのを作りました。
I made this because it was something I really wanted.
イラストはさめあんこ先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei.
可愛いでしょ。この真ん中の穴に、あの、ギュッてペットボトルのところを入れてね、
Isn't it cute? You squeeze the bottle neck into this middle hole...
あの、使うやつです。はい、めっちゃおしゃれです。
...and that's how you use it. It's super stylish!
よかったら使ってください。カバンとかね、つけて持ち運べるんでね。
Please use it if you'd like. You can attach it to your bag to carry it around.
はい。
Yes!
そしてラストは、こちら！
And finally, here is the last one!
はい。実は地味になかった、セーラー服Ver.の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ！
A sailor uniform version plushie of Kazama Iroha, which we surprisingly didn't have!
なんとボイス付きです！
And it actually comes with voices!
こちらもさめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました。
Sameanko-sensei also designed the draft for this one.
レインポンチョを着た、声が出るぬいぐるみです。
It's a talking plushie wearing a rain poncho.
まあ、おてて握りしめると、音が出るらしいぞ。
Apparently, if you squeeze its hand, it makes a sound.
今のところはな、はい。
At least, for now. Yes!
外出時にカバンなどに付けることもできます。
You can also attach it to your bag when you go out.
で、ボイスなんですけど、なんか天気に関するものを録ったんですよ。
As for the voices, I recorded some weather-related lines.
どんな感じかまだ、流石に言えないけど。
I can't tell you exactly what they are yet, of course.
だけど、おみくじ感覚で聞いて、
But you can listen to it like a fortune-telling slip,
あの、その天気にならなかったからといって風真いろはを責めないでください。
and please don't blame me if the weather doesn't turn out like that.
自己責任で、もうニギニギしてください。買ってからのお楽しみです。
Squeeze it at your own risk. It's a surprise for after you buy it!
いっぱいありましたが、フルセット見ていきましょう。
We had a lot of items, but let's take a look at the full set.
こちら！
Here it is!
今回のグッズはですね、生誕のイメージに合わせて、フェス風をテーマに作ってみました。
For this merchandise, we themed it around a festival style to match my birthday image.
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで、
It's highly practical and perfect for the upcoming season,
よかったら、よろしくお願いします。
so please check it out.
そしてフルセット購入特典は、え、こちら。
And the bonus for purchasing the full set is this.
数量限定版あります。
There is a limited-edition quantity version.
風真いろはの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード、ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね。
It includes a ticket-style card with a hand-signed signature and foil-stamped message. Quite stylish, isn't it?
そして通常版には箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます。
And the standard version comes with a foil-stamped printed signature and message ticket-style card.
さらにどちらにも、えー、まあ、ボイスがついてきますね。はい。
In addition, both versions come with a bonus voice track.
「きみと雨宿り」という、なんかタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど、
It's titled "Sheltering from the Rain with You."
まあ、ぶっちゃけあの、気になったら聞いてください。
Honestly, please give it a listen if you are interested.
ボイスは無理して出し、出した、出しそうになったからね。
I strained my voice recording it, or at least I almost did!
はい。ということで。まあシチュエーションボイスですね。
Yes, so it's a situation voice.
雨宿り系だった気が、なんか照れながら録った気がします。
I think it's about sheltering from the rain. I recall being quite embarrassed while recording it.
そしてグッズは21時カートオープンです。すいません。
And the merchandise cart opens at 21:00. Sorry,
あの、生配信につき、ちょっと時間が押しそうなんですけど、
あの、
since this is a live broadcast, we're running a bit behind schedule.
ゆっくり買ってねとは言えず、
But I can't tell you to take your time buying it...
頑張ってください。ごめん、言いようがない。
So please do your best! Sorry, I don't know how else to say it.
そしてあの、21時からホロカート、ホロの、多分配信、控えてると思うんですけど、
And starting from 21:00, there's probably a HoloEarth stream coming up,
あの、何も気にしなくていいんで、スタートしてくださいね。はい。
but please don't worry about us and go ahead and start it, okay?
そして、まだまだあります。まだまだ。
And we still have more. There's more!
それが、こちら！
That would be this!
はい、新曲！イェーイ！
Yes, a new song! Yay!
風真いろはさん、新曲が出ます。タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」。
Kazama Iroha has a new song coming out! The title is "Kazamuki Entropy."
作詞作曲は「いろはステップ」でもお馴染み、40mPさんにしていただきました！
It was written and composed by 40mP, who is well known for "Iroha Step"!
はい。配信後にこちらMVが、えーと、公開されます。
Yes, the music video will be released after this stream.
多分こっそり今マネちゃんが、プレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず。
My manager is probably switching it to a premiere release right now in secret.
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The digital release is scheduled for midnight!
はい、そしてあの、ちょっと気づいた人もいるかもしれないんですけど、
Also, some of you might have noticed this already,
ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました。はい。
but I wrote the text on the jacket cover myself. Yes!
ありがとうございます。ということで、
Thank you so much! And with that,
もう終わっちゃうんですけど、
we are almost at the end.
なんかすごいトレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました。くそ！
But I just got word that we're trending at number 2! Awesome!
あと残り、頑張ってくれと言いたいけど、
I want to tell you to keep pushing for the rest,
でもみんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとうね。
but thank you so much to everyone for posting so much!
よし。準備できた？
All right, are you ready?
音の準備はできてそうなので、さっそく新曲、歌っていきたいと思います。
It looks like the audio is ready, so I'll sing my new song right away.
しかし、今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました。
However, I've prepared something special for today.
ゴンドラ！来い！
Gondola, come here!
おお！
Oh!
リハーサルで見たけど、やっぱいいなこれ。
I saw it during rehearsal, but this is really great.
はい。というわけで、
Yes, so,
みんなぽこべえがいなくて寂しかったでしょ。
everyone must have felt lonely without Pokobei, right?
今年は、ゴンドラになりました！
This year, he has become a gondola!
はい。というわけで、さっそくやっていくんですが、
Yes. So, let's get right to it.
ドア、オープン！
Door, open!
イェーイ。ほっ。乗っちゃうもんね。
Yay! Up I go. I'm boarding it!
というわけで、
And so,
さっそく歌っていきたいと思います。
I'd like to sing the song now.
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは新オリジナル曲、「風向きエントロピー」
Please listen to Kazama Iroha's new original song: "Kazamuki Entropy."
ねぇ いつからそこにいたの？
Hey, since when have you been there?
あまりにも近すぎて気付けなかったよ
You were so close that I didn't even notice.
ずっと私が生まれた日から
All along, since the day I was born...
そばにいてくれたのね
...you have stayed by my side, haven't you?
曖昧で
Vague,
複雑で
complex,
予測不可能で
and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わっていく空の模様
just like the pattern of the ever-changing sky.
想像していたように うまく笑えない
I can't smile as well as I had imagined.
だけどそれ以上に 世界は優しくて
But even more than that, the world is so kind.
いつか風が生まれた
Someday, a wind was born...
足跡が始まる場所
...at the place where footprints begin.
あの角曲がって 戻って 帰って
Even if I turn that corner, turn back, go home...
駆け出したとしても ここに来るんだろう
...and run out, I'll still end up here.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice...
私を彩るすべて
...everything that colors who I am.
方向なんてまだ分からないけど
I still don't know the direction,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just go where the wind blows.
ねえ いつから気づいていたの？
Hey, since when did you notice?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
It's as if you can see right through me.
苦し紛れに誤魔化した嘘も
Even the desperate lies I used to cover things up...
君にはバレていたのかな
...I wonder if you saw through them too.
平凡で退屈で あくびはさびて
Ordinary and boring, yawns growing rusty...
変化のない巡りあわせる時間
...in the unchanging time we share.
想像していただけじゃ何も変わらない
Just imagining it wouldn't change a thing.
だけどそれ以上に
But even more,
予測してた以上に ほら
even more than I predicted, look...
新しい風が吹いてきて
...a new wind has started to blow.
不器用な自分がやけに愛しく思えたんだ
My clumsy self suddenly felt so incredibly dear to me.
いつか風が止んで
When the wind eventually dies down...
足跡が途切れた場所
...at the place where the footprints fade.
落とし物探して 拾って 見つけだせたから
I'll search for what was lost, pick it up, and because I found it...
ここにいるんだろう
...I am here.
そっと 髪がなびく
Gently, my hair flutters in the breeze.
いつか風が夢見た
Someday, where the wind dreamed...
青空と交わる場所
...of meeting the blue sky.
回り道選んで 迷って つまずいたとしても
Even if I take detours, get lost, and stumble...
そこへ行くんだろう
...I'll still make my way there.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice...
私を彩るすべて
...everything that colors who I am.
等身大の手で握りしめて
I hold it tight with my own honest hands.
想像以上にもっと自由な速度で
Moving even faster and more freely than I ever imagined.
方向なんてまだ分からないけど
I still don't know the direction,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just go where the wind blows.
はい、というわけで、ありがとうございました！
All right, and with that, thank you so much!
よいしょ。みんな、すっかり汗かいたわけだけど
Phew. Everyone must be completely sweaty by now, but...
今日これから、記念撮影します！
...from here on, we're going to take a commemorative photo!
そう、お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
That's right, didn't I mention there'd be a souvenir?
これこれ、これ、あ、ちょっと待って、
This is it! Ah, wait a second...
マジで自撮り棒、これリハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに、
Seriously, this selfie stick... I practiced using it so much during rehearsal!
自撮り棒下手。あ、いい感じいい感じ！
I'm so bad at using selfie sticks. Oh, this is good, this is good!
よし、行けそう行けそう。おっけー。
Great, looks like it's working. Okay!
はい！というわけで、皆さん、今日お土産ありって言いましたね？
Yes! So, everyone, I mentioned earlier that there would be a souvenir today, right?
そうなんです！今日撮った、今このござるがね、
That's right! The selfie I, Gozaru, just took...
自撮り棒で撮った写真が、コンビニで！なんと、プリントアウトできます！
...with this selfie stick can actually be printed out at convenience stores!
すごーい！
That's amazing!
はい、こちらですね、対象店舗
Yes! The participating locations are...
ファミリーマートさん、ローソンさん、ミニストップさんで
...FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop.
本日21時から、えー、ネットで事前購入ができます。
You can purchase it online starting tonight at 9:00 PM.
お値段がですね、税込み300円とのことでのことで、
The price is 300 yen (tax included),
印刷できるのは、明日の6月19日、えー、20時からになっております。
and printing will be available starting tomorrow, June 19th, at 8:00 PM.
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、あの、この後書きますんで。はい。
As for the photo, I'll be writing a printed handwritten message on it after this. Yes!
どんな写真が撮れているか、ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒らないでね？
Please don't get mad at me if the photo turned out a bit clumsy!
あの、内容は買ってから確認してください。
You'll have to see the actual photo after you buy it.
いや、すごいよね。ちょっと、いち早く皆さんの元に、
It's pretty amazing, isn't it? I really wanted to get...
あの、なんか手元に残るライブのお土産が用意できればということで
...a physical memento of this live show to you all as quickly as possible,
今回やらせていただきました。お土産あります！
which is why we decided to do this. We have souvenirs!
ちょっと、皆さん各自で回収...
So, please go grab yours...
それだけが申し訳ないんですが お土産ありますので
I'm sorry about that, but we have souvenirs for you,
ぜひ気になったら コンビニプリントしてみてください！
so if you're interested, please try the convenience store print!
そしてコンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日17時59分までです！
And you can purchase the prints until July 21st, 5:59 PM!
概要欄に写真購入のリンクを
The link to purchase the photos...
多分今マネちゃんがやってくれてると思いますので よろしくお願いします！
...is in the description, which Mane-chan is probably setting up right now!
そしてこの後はですね MVの公開と
And after this, we have the music video release...
メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので そちらも絶対来てくださいね！
...and the membership-only encore live, so please make sure to come watch!
それでは皆様！またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone! Let's meet again!
最高の誕生日でした！
It was the best birthday ever!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!